ericsson.net 2010-12-31

# Internet privacy policy (including cookies) - Ericsson

**At Ericsson, we understand that privacy is an important issue for users of, and visitors to, the Ericsson Internet site www.ericsson.com and its related domains. The following information is designed to help visitors understand what information we collect from our site, and how we handle and use the information after that.**

## Information collection and use

Ericsson is the sole owner of any information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. Ericsson may collect information from our users at several different points on our website. Ericsson may also transfer the information collected to any relevant unit within Ericsson, and located anywhere in the world. 

## General inquiries

If a user contacts Ericsson with a general inquiry, the user may need to provide Ericsson with personal information (for example contact details). Ericsson will use this personal information to respond to the inquiry and track further correspondence. Information is also used to compile statistics on response handling, etc. This is done in aggregate, and no individual names or other personal information are retained. Personal information collected is not used for any other purpose. 

## Cookies

Cookies are small text files that a site transfers to a user's (visitor's) hard disk or browser for added functionality or for tracking site usage. In order to measure the effectiveness of our online presence, Ericsson may use cookies to determine the path users take on our site and to identify repeat users of our site. We do not use cookies to gather personal information such as a person's name or e-mail address.

Cookies can be saved to the hard disk, but so-called session cookies are saved to the browser only and disappear when the browser is closed. On the ericsson.com homepage (and similar top or index pages), we use cookies that are saved to the hard disk and therefore remain after the browser is closed. Such cookies determine the path users take on our site and also identify repeat users of our site, although not by names or email addresses. On other pages of our site, we use session cookies to determine the path users take on our site. On some pages, we may also use non-session cookies.

It is possible to configure your browser to reject cookies by modifying the browser settings or preferences. If you wish to do so, we recommend you consult the information provided in the browser or contact the browser vendor for help and instructions.

Any information gathered by the use of cookies is compiled on an aggregate, anonymous basis. 

## Subscriptions 

If a user wishes to subscribe to Ericsson information such as press releases or financial reports, we ask for an email address. Ericsson will use this e-mail address only to send the requested information; we will not send other unsolicited information.

How to subscribe and unsubscribe: Users may open or cancel subscription(s) at any time by filling in the form on [ http://www.ericsson.com/ericsson/press/subscribe/index.shtml](http://www.ericsson.com/ericsson/press/subscribe/index.shtml).

## Orders, surveys and contests

We request information from the user on our order form. Here a user must provide contact information (such as name and shipping address) and, sometimes, financial information (credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fulfill customer orders. If we have trouble processing an order, this contact information is used to get in touch with the user. 

From time to time our site may request information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary, and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and address), and demographic information (such as gender, age, level of education). Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. For contests, contact information will be used to register participants, notify the winners and award prizes, etc. 

## Third-party services

We may partner with another party to provide these or other specific services. When the user signs up for these services, we will share names, or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services.

_These parties are not allowed to use any personal information collected except for the purpose of providing these services. We do not share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers._

## Extranets

Extranets provide customer-specific content and functions. For this site to properly fulfill its obligation to Ericsson's major customers, we must mutually agree on which personnel may access specific extranet content and use specific extranet functions. Ericsson uses cookies, together with additional security mechanisms, to identify and track the registered users who enter extranet or other restricted-access portions of www.ericsson.com (and its related domains). 

## External links

This site may contain links to other sites. Please take note that Ericsson is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this site. 

## Changes to Ericsson's Internet privacy policy

Ericsson may, from time to time, make changes to this policy. We recommend that users of this site re-visit this privacy policy on occasion to learn of new privacy practices or changes to our policy. 

## How to contact Ericsson about this privacy policy

It's important to us at Ericsson to hear what users have to say about our services, and our policies. If site users have any questions, concerns, or complaints about this privacy policy, or want to let us know what they think about any of our off-line and on-line products and services, they can use our "Questions and comments" form accessible from almost every page on this site.
